William N. Damron, Jr. Scrapbooks, 1948-2006
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
William N. Damron, Jr. Scrapbooks 1948-2006
MS 519
Damron, William N., Jr.
The collection is comprised of personal information, scrapbooks, and programs from performances dated 1948 – 2006. William N. Damron, Jr. was in theater arts where he acted, directed, and designed costumes. Most of his career was designing for different performances all over the west coast in the United States. The collection includes resumes from William M. Damron Jr.’s career. There are also fifteen scrapbooks starting from his kindergarten years all the way through the University of Arizona, and ending with his working years in 2006. They contain newspaper clippings, pasted programs, thank you cards, congratulation cards, costume design sketches, and photographs of William N. Damron, Jr.’s performance, drama career in acting, directing and mostly costume design. The collection also has loose program from performances that are not embedded in the scrapbooks. Some highlights of the performances are from the University of Arizona 1962 – 1979 thought his college years, and costume design in award shows like the Grammy’s, the Academy Awards. He also designed for the Los Angeles opera.
4 Linear Feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collections
Biographical Note
William N. Damron, Jr. was in the theater profession in where he acted, directed and primarily did costumes designs for different performances all over the west coast of the United States. As a Tucson native, he documented his life through scrapbooks. He attended Alice Vail middle school where his love of performance began with tap dancing. During his Rincon High School years he participated in the choir program. In the University of Arizona he received a Bachelor degree of Fine Arts in Drama production, a Masters of Arts in Drama Production with an emphasis in costume design and a Master’s in Fine Arts in Costume Design. For a short time he also taught at the University of Redlands. Most of his career was spend in costumes design for important theater productions in the Colorado, Los Angeles, Las Vegas and Tucson. Some highlights of his career were costume design at the Los Angeles Opera, the Grammy Awards, and the Academy awards.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 3 series
Series I Personal Information, undated
Series II Programs, 1955-1997
Series III Scrapbooks, 1948-2006
Scope and Content Note
This collection is of Tucson native’s William N. Damron, Jr.’s personal resumes, scrapbooks, and programs from performances, date 1948 – 2006. This collection contains personal information, but mostly scrapbooks and programs from performances collected by William N. Damron, Jr. The bulk of the materials consist of Damron’s own career in the theater arts. His personal documents include work resumes of his performance career. The resumes include; education, theater, television (feature, educational), teaching, director, acting, acting, professional work, costume design, roles played at the University of Arizona. The scrapbooks contain newspaper clippings, thank you cards, costume design sketches, photographs, programs and other performance and life related materials. The programs are those performance programs that are not already attached in the scrapbooks.
Access Terms
Scrapbooks
Theater Programs--Arizona--Tucson
Performance
Photographs
Correspondence
Clipplings (Books, newspaper, etc.)
Acting--Drama
Theater--Production and Directing
Costume design
University of Arizona
Los Angeles Opera
Academy Awards (Motion Pictures)
Tucson Unified School District (Pima County, Ariz.)
Tucson (Ariz.)
Container List
- Series I: Personal Information undated
  This series is arranged by alphabetical order by the type of documents. It contains resumes of William N. Damron, Jr.
  - Resumes, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Series II: Prograpms 1955-1997
  This series is arranged chronologically with undated first. It contains loose programs that were not originally placed in the scrapbooks.
  - Programs, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Programs, 1955-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Programs, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Programs, 1976-1997 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Series III: Scrapbooks, 1948-2006
  These 15 scrapbooks are arranged chronologically by date. These scrapbooks contain programs, newspaper clippings, sketches, thank you cards/flower cards, and photographs.
  - Scrapbook, 1948-1958 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1958-1962 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1966 (Box 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1966-1968 (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1968-1971 (Box 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1971-1973 (Box 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1973-1976 (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1977-1980 (Box 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1980-1981 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1983-1989 (Box 11)
  - Scrapbook, 1989-1994 (Box 12)
  - Scrapbook, 1994-1997 (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook, 1999-2000 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook, 2000-2003 (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook, 2004-2006 (Box 16)